Hmong Community Folklife and Documentation Project collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Hmong Community Folklife and Documentation Project collection 1981-1986
AFC 2007/026
International House of Philadelphia. Folklife Center
approximately 2,474 items
11 containers
0.5 linear feet
698 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm
5 photographs: color transparencies; half frame 35 mm
789 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 35 mm
102 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 120 format
296 photographs: film negatives, color; 35 mm
69 photographs: prints, black and white; various sizes
9 photographs: prints, color; various sizes
73 photographs: contact sheets, black and white; various sizes
59 sound cassettes: analog
44 videocassettes (U-matic video): analog
2 videocassettes (VHS): analog
2 videocassettes (Betamax): analog
2 film reels (1 in.): analog
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of audio and video field recordings and photographs documenting the Hmong community in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
Provenance
Donated by Catherine Jacobs, 2007.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Hmong Community Folklife and Documentation Project collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Administrative History
The Hmong Community Folklife and Documentation Project was a joint effort of the Folklife Center of International House and the Hmong community in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania from 1981 to 1986. The staff included community coordinator Chao Song, project director Carole Boughter, media coordinator Barry Dornfeld, Ellen McHale, Mal O'Connor, Sally Peterson, Margaret A. Mills, Yer Hang, Bee Lo, Moua Lo, Phua Xiong, Hang Sai, Chakarin Sirirathasuk, and Mai Vang Xiong. The project was funded by the National Endowment for the Arts Folk Arts Program, the Pennsylvania Council for the Arts, CIGNA Foundation, and the Sun Company.
Scope and Content
The collection contains audio and video field recordings and photographs documenting the Hmong community in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, between 1981 to 1986. Documentation covers daily life; community celebrations including Hmong New Year celebrations, baby naming ceremonies, and weddings; and traditional arts like paj ntaub needlework, Hmong instruments, music, and dance. Interviews with community members were conducted in Hmong and some have English summaries. Also included in the collection are brochures, an index to the interviews, completed recording log forms, photo logs, and copies of a documentary titled Years Away from Laos: The Hmong in Philadelphia.
Arrangement
The Hmong Community Folklife and Documentation Project collection is organized in 6 series:
Series 1: Interviews
Series 2: Community celebrations
Series 3: Traditional arts
Series 4: Community daily life
Series 5: Years Away from Laos: The Hmong in Philadelphia documentary project
Series 6: Project documentation
Materials are arranged chronologically within each series.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Dornfeld, Barry, 1958-
Organizations
International House of Philadelphia. Folklife Center.
Subjects
Hmong (Asian people)--Music.; Hmong Americans--Music.; Hmong Americans--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Interviews.; Hmong Americans--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Social life and customs.; Hmong New Year--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.; Needlework, Hmong--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.
Places
Philadelphia (Pa.)--Social life and customs.
Titles
Years away from Laos: the Hmong in Philadelphia
Form/Genre
Ethnographic films.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Oral histories.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videocassettes.
Container List
- Series 1: Interviews
  - Interview component #1, Traung session, September 8, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR58; 1 sound cassette
  - Chao Song interview, September 16, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR19; ML 001; 1 sound cassette
  - Xia Kao Xiong interview, October 6, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR26, SR27, SR32, SR42; BL+ML 001, BL+ML 002; 4 sound cassettes
  - Xia Kao Xiong interview at his home, October 6, 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH066; 35 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Pang Kao Hang interview, November 17, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR29, SR52, SR25; ML+YH 001, ML+YH 002; 3 sound cassettes
  - Xia Kao Xiong interview, November 17, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR01, SR43, SR46, SR14, SR30; BL+PX 003, BL+PX 004; 5 sound cassettes
  - Pang Kao Hang interview, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH002; 32 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
  - Pang Kao Hang interview, January 1985, AFC 2007/026: SR18, SR47; ML+YH 002, ML+YH 003; 2 sound cassettes
  - Va Cheng Hang interview, January 12, 1985, AFC 2007/026: SR04, SR41, SR07, SR40; BL+PX 005, BL+PX 006; 4 sound cassettes
  - Yer's father interview, January 26, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH049; 13 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Va Cheng Hang interview, January 27, 1985, AFC 2007/026: SR33, SR23, SR12, SR57, SR08, SR22; BL+PX 007, BL+PX 008, BL+PX 009; 6 sound cassettes
  - Pang Xiong Sirirathasuk, Yee Vang Lo, and Mao Vang Xiong interview, February 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: SR06, SR09, SR16, SR10, SR20, SR36; YH+PX 001, YH+PX 002, YH+PX 003; 6 sound cassettes
  - Men's group interview, February 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: SR15, SR24, SR45, SR48; ML+BL 001, ML+BL 002, ML+BL 003; 4 sound cassettes
  - Men's group interview at St. Simeon's Church, February 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV23, MV24, MV25, MV26; 4 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - Women's group interview, February 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV18, MV19, MV20; 3 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - Women's group interview and music, February 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV21; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Tong Song Moua interview, March 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: SR05, SR44, SR34; ML+BL 004, ML+BL 005; 3 sound cassettes
  - Unknown participant interview, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV36; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Unknown participant interview, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV01, MV02; 2 videocassettes (U-matic)
- Series 2: Community celebrations
  - Back Mountain Folk Fest, 1981, AFC 2007/026: PH028; 4 color slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
  - Hmong meeting for New Year Halloween party, November 10-11, 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH053; 21 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - New Year's preparation and dance rehearsal, November 22, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR49; PX+BL (SH) 005; 1 sound cassette
  - Hmong New Year Huntington Park and I-House morning, November 23, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR55; BL+HS; 1 sound cassette
  - New Year's celebration I-House 3:00pm, November 23, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR50; SP+HS 001; 1 sound cassette
  - New Year's Day and preparations, November 23, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR31; PX+BL 007; 1 sound cassette
  - New Year's Day (first day), November 23, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR51; PX+BL (SH) 006; 1 sound cassette
  - New Year (1985) Hunting Park, November 23, 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH038; 66 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - New Year I-House, November 23, 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH050; 10 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - International House up to 4:30pm/Hmong New Year, November 23-24, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR37; PX; 1 sound cassette
  - New Year's celebration, November 24, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR28, SR53, SR59; SP+HS+MOC, BD+MOC, SH; 3 sound cassettes
  - New Year International House, November 24, 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH054; 21 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Tou Hang and Chou Lor's wedding, December 8, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR13, SR21; PX+BL 009, BL+PX (SH); 2 sound cassettes
  - Hmong New Year '84 (Mills), 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH007; 25 color slides (35 mm); 5 color slides (half frame 35 mm) (Box 8)
  - Hmong New Year '84 (Peterson), 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH008; 43 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
  - Hmong New Year '84 (staff), 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH009; 29 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Hmong New Year '84 (staff), 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH010; 23 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Hmong New Year '84 (staff), 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH011; 16 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Hmong New Year '84 (staff), 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH012; 37 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Hmong New Year '84 (staff), 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH013; 26 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Hmong New Year celebration, 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH032; 19 color slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
  - Community events, circa 1984-1985, AFC 2007/026: PH081; 19 black-and-white prints (various sizes); 3 color prints (various sizes) (Box 3)
  - Baby naming, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH005; 37 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
  - Baby naming party, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH024; 28 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Baby naming party, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH025; 19 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - D.C. Inaugural party (Sirirathasuk), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH014; 65 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous events, circa 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH026; 20 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous events, circa 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH031; 5 color slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous events, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH042; 22 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous events, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH070; 36 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - New Year's, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH051; 36 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - New Year's party, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH056; 11 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Wedding at Pan Yor Lo's, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH062; 30 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Wedding at Pan Zer Lo's, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH055; 30 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Youth Halloween party, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH043; 46 black-and-white negatives (120 format) (Box 6)
  - Youth Halloween party, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH067; 6 black-and-white negatives (120 format) (Box 6)
- Series 3: Traditional arts
  - Traditional arts, circa 1984-1985, AFC 2007/026: PH082; 4 black-and-white prints (8x10 in.) (Box 3)
  - Xia Kao storytelling, February 9, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV07, MV08; 2 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - Hmong craft ladies, February 10, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH039; 14 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Paj ntaub apprenticeship, March 23, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV27, MV28; 2 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - Craft sale paj ntaub (Westerman), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH006; 31 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
  - Paj ntaub apprenticeship PCA (Peterson), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH022; 25 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Paj ntaub apprenticeship PCA (Sirirathasuk), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH023; 30 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Paj ntaub for PCA apprenticeship application, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH004; 8 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
  - Sheboygan exhibit paj ntaub, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH001; 10 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
  - Craft sale, circa 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH034; 15 color slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
  - Hmong textiles, circa 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH027; 7 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Hmong textiles, circa 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH035; 8 color slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
  - Cambodian and Vietnamese dancers in D.C., Xing Choa-Sam's place, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH063; 19 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Dance performance, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH036; 12 black-and-white negatives (120 format) (Box 6)
  - Dance performance, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH061; 12 black-and-white negatives (120 format) (Box 6)
  - Dance performance, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH071; 37 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Dance performance, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH074; 22 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Dance performance, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH076; 22 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Dance performance, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH077; 23 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Dancers in Christmas party, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH058; 10 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Hmong textiles, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH073; 22 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Hmong textiles, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH079; 40 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Musical performances, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH047; 12 black-and-white negatives (120 format) (Box 6)
  - Talent show, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH072; 37 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Thaum Ntuj Tsim Teb Raug ( The Beginning of the World ), ESL Level 1 (photocopy), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/1)
- Series 4: Community daily life
  - Lea School performance, 1981, AFC 2007/026: PH029; 3 color slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
  - Paley performance and sale, 1981, AFC 2007/026: PH030; 10 color slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
  - Exterior stills, September 13, 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH080; 32 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Yang's party and Vang Pao assistant having dinner at Pang's home, September 18, 1984, AFC 2007/026: PH069; 35 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Meeting and choose the new leader of the youth, December 2, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR35; YH 003; 1 sound cassette
  - Meeting of the old group people, December 2, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR11; YH 005; 1 sound cassette
  - The old group meeting and the youth group, December 2, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR56; YH 004; 1 sound cassette
  - Community daily life, circa 1984-1985, AFC 2007/026: PH083; 3 color prints (various sizes); 26 black-and-white prints (8x10 in.) (Box 4)
  - Hmong store, February 9, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV06; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Paua Xiong's violin lesson at Settlement Music School, February 9, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV04, MV05; 2 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - Church service at Incarnation, February 10, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV09, MV10, MV11; 3 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - Hmong church service, February 10, 1985, AFC 2007/026: SR02, SR03; 2 sound cassettes
  - Pang Yer Lor and family at home, February 10, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV12, MV13, MV14; 3 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - Skating time, February 12, 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH068; 29 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Hua Lor working with a computer at CCP; outside of Hmong store; young people in Yang's living room, February 23, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV15; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Card playing in Yang's house; Yang at cemetery, February 23-24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV16; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Yang in cemetery; driving scenes of Philadelphia (West); women's group interview, February 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV17; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Pang Xiong Sirirathasuk playing; work at Friday, Saturday, Sunday; men's group interview - St. Simeon's, February 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV22; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Chuck playing video game; Dua Cuang and Xia Kao at Italian Market, Philadelphia cityscape; youth meeting, March 23-24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV29; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Hang Cua in office at St. Simeon's; Xia Kao and Dua Chang at home, March 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV33; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Outside of Tabernacle Church; taking Dua Chang's measurements (Pang Xiong); rock and roll at Sirirathasuk's house, March 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV31; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Rock and roll at Sirirathasuk's house, March 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV32; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Xia Kao and Dua Chang at home, March 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV34; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Youth meeting; outside of Faith Tabernacle Church, March 24, 1985, AFC 2007/026: MV30; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - House interiors (Sirirathasuk/Hang), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH003; 28 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
  - Roller skating party (Peterson), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH021; 18 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - International House, July 29, 1986, AFC 2007/026: MV49, MV50; 2 video tapes (1-inch)
  - Hmong desk calendar, 1986, 1 folder of manuscripts; 23 black-and-white prints (various sizes) (Box-folder 1/7)
  - At Long M's party, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH059; 38 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Break dancers, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH041; 74 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Break dancers, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH078; 21 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Community members, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH075; 36 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 7)
  - Daily life, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV03; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Exterior stills, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH045; 12 black-and-white negatives (120 format) (Box 6)
  - Exterior stills, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH060; 6 black-and-white negatives (120 format) (Box 6)
  - Exterior stills, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH065; 20 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Game night, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH052; 72 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - January meeting and video training, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH057; 16 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Media team working, Xai's dad, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH048; 19 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Preparing food and practicing the dance, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH040; 35 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Xai's and Chuck's houses (extra), undated, AFC 2007/026: PH064; 27 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Xia Xao Zing's house, kids, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH037; 34 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
- Series 5: Years Away from Laos: The Hmong in Philadelphia documentary project
  - Video production stills (staff), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH015; 8 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Video production stills (staff), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH016; 16 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Video production stills (staff), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH017; 12 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Video production stills (staff), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH018; 11 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Video production stills (staff), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH019; 12 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Video production stills (staff), 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH020; 13 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Video production stills, circa 1985, AFC 2007/026: PH033; 5 color slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
  - The team picking pictures, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH046; 20 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 6)
  - Video production stills, undated, AFC 2007/026: PH044; 6 black-and-white negatives (120 format) (Box 6)
  - Hmong language master copy, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV38; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Master copy, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV39; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Dub copy, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV40, MV41; 2 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - 3/4" copy, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV42, MV43, MV44; 3 videocassettes (U-matic)
  - VHS copy, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV45, MV46; 2 videocassettes (VHS)
  - Hmong language Beta II copy, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV47, MV48; 2 videocassettes (Betamax)
- Series 6: Project documentation
  - Experimental tape, September 16, 1984, AFC 2007/026: SR17; BL; 1 sound cassette
  - Cassette logs and blank forms, 1984, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Cassette logs from binder, 1984, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Cassette logs, plus table of contents, index, and list of keywords, 1984, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Contact sheets, circa 1984-1985, AFC 2007/026: PH084; 73 black-and-white contact sheets (various sizes) (Box 5)
  - Publicity photos, circa 1984-1985, AFC 2007/026: PH085; 20 black-and-white prints (various sizes); 3 color prints (5x7 in.) (Box 2)
  - Experimental tape, undated, AFC 2007/026: SR54; 1 sound cassette
  - Field notes, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Hmong Community Folklife and Documentation Project brochure, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Learning tape, undated, AFC 2007/026: MV37; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
  - Photocopies of moving image carriers, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Slide logs, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Training session tape recording, undated, AFC 2007/026: SR39; PX+BL 008; 1 sound cassette